星舰即将到达鯨魚座ο3号行星，长官
Approaching Omicron Ceti III, sir.
调整轨道，裴恩特先生
Standard orbit, Mr. Painter.
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
- 舰长？ - 怎么了，上尉
- Captain? - Yes, lieutenant.
舰长，我遵照指示
I've been transmitting a contact signal
每5分钟发送一次通讯信号
every five minutes as ordered, sir.
可是完全没有回应
All I get is dead air. Shall I continue?
继续发送信号，直到我们进入轨道
Maintain transmission pattern until we've established orbit.
- 遵命，长官 - 史波克先生
- Aye, aye, sir. - Mr. Spock,
那颗星球上有150名男女和儿童
there were 150 men, women and children in that colony.
你认为他们生还的概率是多少？
What are the chances of survivors?
他们不可能还活着，舰长
Absolutely none, captain.
博托射线是最近才被发现的
Berthold rays are such a recent discovery.
我们还不完全了解它的性质
We do not yet have full knowledge of their nature.
但有一点是确定的
It is known, however, that living animal tissue
这种射线会分解动物组织
disintegrates under exposure.
桑多瓦尔和他的部下们不可能挺过三年
Sandoval's group could not have survived after three years.
你是说他们早知如此
You're saying that those people
却仍试着在那开荒？
built a future in a place knowing they might not survive.
也许他们认为射线并不那么致命
I'm saying they knew there was a risk.
那么我们呢，能不能登陆？
What about us? Can we afford to send people down to the planet surface?
射线的破坏作用需要一个过程
The breakdown of tissue does not develop immediately.
我们能耐受一定程度的辐射
We can risk a limited exposure.
星舰进入轨道，舰长，殖民地已定位
We've established orbit, sir. And I've pinpointed a settlement.
好的，裴恩特
Thank you, Mr. Painter.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
组织一个五人登陆小队
Equip a landing party of five to accompany me
跟随我前往星球表面
to the planet surface.
安排麦考伊和一名生物学家与我们同行
Include Dr. McCoy and a biologist.
让他们在10分钟之内准备好
I'll want them in ten minutes.
又是一次失败的殖民
Another dream that failed.
没有比这更让人伤感的了
There's nothing sadder.
这些人花了一年的时间从地球出发
It took these people a year to make the trip from Earth.
长途跋涉来到这里……
They came all that way...
……然后死去
...and died.
才不是呢，长官
Hardly that, sir.
欢迎来到鯨魚座ο3号行星
Welcome to Omicron Ceti III.
我是伊莱亚斯·桑多瓦尔
I'm Elias Sandoval.
宇宙，最后的边疆
Space, the final frontier.
这是星舰进取号的航程
These are the voyages Of the starship Enterprise.
它的五年任务，是去探索未知的新世界
Its five-year mission: To explore strange new worlds,
找寻新的生命和新的文明
to seek out new life and new civilizations,
勇敢地航向前人未至之境
to boldly go where no man has gone before.
【星际迷航：原初】
TLF荣誉出品
本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
-=TLF字幕组=-
翻译：Nick
校对：喜马拉雅
第一季第二十四集
人间天堂
舰长日志，星历3417.3
Captain's log, stardate 3417.3.
我们本以为此次鯨魚座ο3号之旅
We thought our mission to Omicron Ceti III
将会充满悲伤
would be an unhappy one.
我们早已断定这个殖民地再无生还者
We had expected to find no survivors of the agricultural colony there.
但显然，我们错了
Apparently, our information was incorrect.
我们离开地球已有四年了
We haven't seen anyone outside our own group for four years
这期间从未遇到过其他人
since we left the Earth.
我们一直在等候你们这些客人
We've been expecting someone for some time.
我们的子空间无线电设备无法正常运作
Our subspace radio didn't work properly.
而且这里也没有人
I'm afraid we didn't have anyone here
会修理这复杂的设备
who could master its intricacies.
桑多瓦尔先生
Actually, Mr. Sandoval,
我们并不是因为你们的设备故障而来的
we didn't come here because of your silent radio.
无论你们为何而来，我们都欢迎你们
It makes little difference, captain. You're here. We're happy to see you.
来，我带你们参观一下定居点
Come, let me show you our settlement.
根据我的观察
On pure speculation, just an educated guess,
那是个活人
I'd say that man is alive.
舰长，我们的情报表明
Captain, this planet is being bombarded by Berthold rays,
这颗行星正受到博托射线的照射
as our reports indicated.
我们能在这种强度的辐射中安全地存活一周
At this intensity, we'll be safe for a week, if necessary.
但是……
But...
但是这些人不应该还活着
But these people shouldn't be alive.
难道他们已经死了？
Is it possible that they're not?
你不是握手了吗，吉姆？
You shook hands with him, Jim.
他的手是暖的，他还活着
His flesh was warm. He's alive.
这毫无疑问
There's no doubt about that.
但博托射线是致命的
There is also no question on the fact
这也同样毫无疑问
that Berthold rays are incontrovertibly deadly.
你要知道，麦考伊
There's no miracle connected with it, doctor. You know that.
足够剂量的辐射会杀死人
No cures, no serums, no antidotes.
无法治疗，没有血清和解药
If a man is exposed long enough, he dies.
各位，多说无益
Gentlemen, we're debating in a vacuum.
还是一起去寻找答案吧
Let's go get some answers.
我们还有另外两处村落，而这里有45名居民
There are two other settlements, but we have 45 colonists here.
为什么要分散开来？
What was the reason for the dispersal?
分成三处的话
Well, we felt that three groups
繁衍壮大的可能性更高
would have a better chance for growth.
如果疾病侵袭了其中一个村落
If disease were to strike one group,
另外两处不易受到影响
then the others would be less likely to be affected.
ο星非常适合农业开发
You see, Omicron is an ideal agricultural planet.
在我们之前，失败的先例有很多
We determined not to suffer
但我们绝不希望重蹈覆辙
the fate of expeditions that went before us.
伊莱亚斯
Elias.
利拉，来见见我们的客人
Leila, come meet our guests.
这是我们的植物学家利拉·卡罗米
This is Leila Kalomi, our botanist.
这是寇克舰长，麦考伊医生，史波克先生
This is Captain Kirk, Dr. McCoy, Mr. Spock.
史波克先生和我曾有过一面之缘
Mr. Spock and I have met before.
在很久以前
It's been a long time.
桑多瓦尔先生，我们来这里是有任务的
Mr. Sandoval, we do have a mission here.
- 需要进行一系列检查，测试 - 没问题
- Examinations. Tests. - By all means, make them.
我相信你们会对这里感兴趣
I think you'll find our settlement an interesting one.
我们有一个很简单的理想
Our philosophy is a simple one:
那就是让人类回归简单的生活
That men should return to a less-complicated life.
我们这里机器很少
We have few mechanical things here.
没有车辆，也没有武器
No vehicles, no weapons.
我们这里没有暴力，充满和平
We have harmony here. Complete peace.
我们会尽量避免干扰你们
We'll try not to interfere with your work.
请自便吧，先生们
Make yourselves at home, gentlemen.
我们到底要找什么呢，长官？
What exactly are we looking for anyway, sir?
任何看起来不正常的东西
Whatever doesn't look right. Whatever that is.
我不熟悉农场
When it comes to farms,
只有靠近点看
I wouldn't know what looked right or wrong
才能发现问题所在
if it were 2 feet from me.
嘿
Hey.
怎么了？
What is it?
没有牛
No cows.
这棚子并不用来圈养牲口，而是用来存放东西
This barn isn't even built for them, just for storage.
仔细想想
Come to think of it,
我们好像没见过任何动物
we haven't seen any animals.
没有马，没有猪，连狗都没有
No horses, no pigs. Not even a dog.
没有任何牲畜
Nothing.
你认识那个瓦肯星人
You've known the Vulcanian.
是的，六年前在地球上
On Earth. Six years ago.
你爱他吗？
Did you love him?
我暗恋着他
If I did, it was important only to myself.
那么他呢？
How did he feel?
他从未流露过他对我的感觉
Mr. Spock's feelings were never expressed to me.
据说他没有情感
It is said he has none to give.
那你现在希望他留下来，成为我们的一员吗？
Would you like him to stay with us now? To be as one of us?
他会留下来的，伊莱亚斯
There is no choice, Elias.
他别无选择
He will stay.
可以了，谢谢你的配合
That will be all. Thank you very much.
有什么发现吗？
Anything?
我已经检查了9名男性，年龄从23到59岁不等
I've examined nine men so far, varying in ages from 23 to 59.
他们的健康状况都很完美
They're all in perfect condition. Textbook responses.
心肺功能极佳
Heart, lungs, excellent.
协调度极佳
Coordination, excellent.
神经反射正常
Reflexes, excellent.
如果所有人都像他们这样，我就可以扔掉行医执照了
If there were many more of them, I could throw away my shingle.
我是寇克
Kirk here.
我是史波克，舰长
Spock here, captain.
除了殖民地居民
There seems to be a total absence of life on the planet
以及各种植被
with the exception of the colonists themselves
这颗星球上似乎没有其他生物
and various types of flora.
这和苏鲁的观察一致
Sulu had the same observation.
怎么回事？
Any explanations?
现在还不清楚，长官
Not at the moment, sir.
我正在使用三录仪进行各种测试
I'm conducting various tests with the tricorder,
但还没得到结论
but results are inconclusive.
很好，继续进行调查，寇克呼叫完毕
Very well. Continue investigations. Kirk out.
没有动物，真是奇怪
No animals. That's peculiar.
没错，而且根据记录
Yes, especially in view of the fact
他们曾经饲养过一些动物
that the records of this expedition indicate that they did have some
用于繁殖、食用
for breeding and food purposes.
显然，它们都没能活下来
Apparently, none of them survived.
我想看看他们的医疗记录
I'd like to see the medical records on the expedition.
是的，我想你应该看看
Yes, I thought you might.
舰长，我在找你呢
Captain, I've been looking for you.
你还没参观过我们的田地和作物吧
You haven't seen our fields and crops.
我想带你们去看看我们的成果
I'd like to show you and the doctor what we've accomplished here.
我恐怕要失陪了
I'm afraid I'll have to bow out.
我还要继续做一些医学检测
I have to continue with these medical examinations.
但如果我发现其他人
However, if I find everyone else's health
也和你一样健康的话，我…
to be as perfect as yours, I...
他就要扔掉他的行医执照了
He promised to throw away his shingle.
我恐怕你是找不到病人了
Well, you'll find no weaklings here.
舰长，请
Captain?
这就是答案，舰长
This is the reason, captain.
所有作物都能在这种土壤中生长
This soil will grow anything we plant in it.
这是一个完美的世界
It's a perfect world.
气候温和
We have a moderate climate.
全年都有适度的降水
Moderate rains all year round.
能为我们提供需要的一切
It gives us all we need.
- 就像是伊甸园 - 舰长，打扰一下
- It is perfect. - Pardon me, captain.
生物报告出来了，长官
Biology report ready, sir.
我有事失陪了，舰长
Well, I have work to tend to myself, captain.
说吧，上尉
Go ahead, lieutenant.
桑多瓦尔说他们能种植任何作物
I heard Sandoval saying they could grow anything here.
事实的确如此，谷类、马铃薯、豆类
That's true, sir. They've got a variety of crops in. Grains, potatoes, beans.
你想说什么
Make your point.
对于一个农业殖民地来说
Well, sir, for an agricultural colony,
他们的耕种面积太小了
they actually have very little acreage planted.
生产的粮食仅够维持生活，几乎没有剩余
There's enough to sustain the colony, but very little more.
这一切实在太奇怪了
It's like a jigsaw puzzle, all one colour.
而我们一点头绪都没有
No key to where the pieces fit in.
到底是怎么回事？
Why?
- 我是寇克 - 我是麦考伊，吉姆
- Kirk here. - This is McCoy, Jim.
- 我想你最好回来一下 - 出什么事了吗？
- I think you better get back here. - Trouble?
没有，但我想让你亲眼看看
No, but I'd like you to see this for yourself.
来了
On my way.
桑多瓦尔的医疗记录显示
Sandoval's medical record
4年前，当此次殖民行动开始时
four years ago, when the expedition left Earth.
仪器检测出了他肺部的疤痕
He registered scar tissue on his lungs
那是他小时候患大叶性肺炎时留下的
from lobar pneumonia suffered when he was a child.
除了切掉阑尾他没动过大手术
No major operations, but there was an appendectomy.
还接受了计划免疫
Received all required inoculations, et cetera.
这有什么奇怪的？
What's so strange about that?
没有
Nothing.
但不到2个小时前我检查过他
But I examined that man not more than two hours ago.
你知道结果如何吗？
And you know what his readings were?
一切都很完美
Perfect, perfect and perfect.
就像这里的其他人一样
Just like everyone else I've examined here.
是仪器发生故障了吗？
Instrument malfunction?
没有，我用它来检测自己的情况
No, I thought of that, and I tested it on myself.
它准确地记录了我的扁桃体切除史
It accurately recorded my lack of tonsils
还有两处肋骨骨折
and those two broken ribs I had once.
它没有检测到桑多瓦尔肺部的瘢痕
It did not record the scar tissue on Sandoval's lungs.
但却检测到他体内有一条健康的阑尾
But it did record a healthy appendix
而那本不应该存在
where one was supposedly removed.
连虫子都没有一条
Nothing. Not even insects.
但作物却在生长，而你们也能在博托射线照射下存活
Yet your plants grow, and you've survived exposure to Berthold rays.
这是可以解释的
That can be explained.
请告诉我
Please do.
再等等吧
Later.
我无法了解为什么女性
I've never understood the female capacity
要回避正面回答问题
to avoid a direct answer to any question.
我也不了解你
And I never understood you.
直到现在
Until now.
从未有人能进入你的内心
There was always a place in here where no one could come.
你总是一副扑克脸
There was only the face you allow people to see.
别人只能看到你的一面
Only one side you'd allow them to know.
我想知道你们
I would like to know how your people
是如何活下来的
have managed to survive here.
我好想你
I missed you.
理论上讲，你们不应该能活下来
Logically, you should all be dead.
如果我解答了你的疑惑
If I tell you how we survived,
你会试着了解我们对这里的生活
will you try to understand how we feel about our life here?
以及对彼此的感受吗？
About each other?
我不知感情为何物，我是个科学家
Emotions are alien to me, I'm a scientist.
你也许骗得过
Someone else might believe that.
你的船员，舰长，或是其他人
Your shipmates, your captain.
但你骗不了我
But not me.
跟我来
Come.
桑多瓦尔先生
Mr. Sandoval, within the hour,
我刚收到来自星舰指挥部的命令
I've received orders from Starfleet Command
需要撤离殖民地所有居民
to evacuate all personnel from this colony.
所以，你应该通知他们开始准备
Naturally, you'll inform your people to begin preparations.
我们会在进取号上为你们提供食宿
We will have accommodations for you aboard the Enterprise.
我拒绝
No.
先生，这并不是我自己的主意
It's not an arbitrary decision on my part, sir.
这是我需要执行的命令
I have my orders.
舰长，这条命令完全是多余的
Captain, it's entirely unnecessary.
我们在这里很安全
We're in no danger here.
我们已经向你解释过博托射线的危害了
We've explained the Berthold rays to you and their effect.
难道你还不清楚吗？
Can't you understand?
医生，我怎么才能让你明白呢？
Doctor, how can l make you understand?
你的仪器已经显示，我们全员都非常健康
Your own instruments have shown that we're all in perfect health.
没有人因为射线而死去
We've had no deaths here.
那你们的牲畜呢？
What about your animals?
我们是素食者
We're vegetarians.
你还没有回答我的问题
That doesn't answer my question, sir.
为什么你们的牲畜都死了？
Why did all your animals die?
舰长，请不要在意这些细枝末节
Captain, you stress very unimportant matters.
我们是不会离开的
We will not leave.
快到了
It's not much further.
你还没告诉我这是什么
You've not yet explained the nature of this thing.
那并不重要
Its basic properties and elements are not important.
重要的是它给我们带来了生命，和平，还有爱
What is important is, it gives life, peace, love.
你所说的…
What you're describing...
…该不会是镇静剂吧
...was once known in the vernacular as a happiness pill.
你是个科学家，应该明白那不能用来抵抗射线
And you, as a scientist, should know that that's not possible.
过来
Come.
我是首批发现
I was one of the first to find them.
这些孢子的人
The spores.
孢子？
Spores?
不
No.
你不应该觉得难受的啊
It shouldn't hurt.
不，我不行
No, I can't.
不要
Please don't.
不应该是这样的，我们都没感受到痛苦
Not like this. It didn't hurt us.
我和你们不一样
I am not like you.
现在
Now.
你已经成为了我们的一员
Now you belong to all of us.
我们都是一样的
And we to you.
你不用再藏着自己了
There's no need to hide your inner face any longer.
我们心意相通
We understand.
我爱你
I love you.
我可以爱你
I can love you.
舰长日志，补充记录
Captain's log, supplemental.
我们受星舰指挥部之令
We have been ordered by starfleet Command
来到ο3号行星撤离当地殖民者
to evacuate the colony on Omicron III.
但是殖民地领袖伊莱亚斯·桑多瓦尔
However, the colony leader, Elias sandoval,
拒绝合作，并且不听取任何意见
has refused all cooperation and will not listen to any arguments.
- 桑多瓦尔 - 舰长，你的要求
- Sandoval. - Captain, your arguments
非常正当，但我们不会接受
are very valid, but they do not apply to us.
你这是在无理取闹
You're being unreasonable.
不好意思，失陪了
Well, nevertheless. Excuse me.
等等
Excuse me.
我的任务是撤离所有的殖民地居民
My orders are to remove all the colonists,
无论你合作与否，我都会完成任务
and that's exactly what I intend to do, with or without your help.
恐怕你要靠自己了
Without, I should think.
要用武力制服他吗，吉姆？
Would you like to use a butterfly net on him, Jim?
- 不，我不希望… - 舰长
- No, I don't think I'll use a-- - Captain.
我们检查了所有东西
We've checked out everything.
除了没见到动物
It all seems normal
一切似乎都正常
except for the absence of any animals.
我们要把居民撤离至第27星际基地
We have orders to evacuate all colonists to Starbase 27.
登陆部队必须协助他们
I want landing parties to coordinate the colonists
准备把他们传送到星舰上
and prepare them to transport up to the ship.
我们需要准备额外的食宿
We'll need extra accommodations aboard.
史波克和德赛尔呢？
Where's Mr. Spock and Mr. DeSalle?
检查工作开始之后我们就没看到过他们
We haven't seen them since we began our check.
德赛尔说他要去看看一些本地植物
DeSalle said he was going to examine some native plants he found.
史波克有呼叫过吗？
Did Spock call in at all?
没有
No, he didn't.
史波克请回复…苏鲁，去看看登陆部队
Spock. See to the landing parties, will you, Mr. Sulu?
遵命，长官
Yes, sir.
史波克
Spock.
那块云看起像就像一条龙
That one looks like a dragon.
你看到尾巴和背脊了吗？
You see the tail and the dorsal spines?
我还没见过龙
I've never seen a dragon.
我见过
I have.
在贝伦加丽亚7号
On Berengaria VII.
我以前没留意过云朵
But I've never stopped to look at clouds before.
还有彩虹
Or rainbows.
我很清楚彩虹形成的原理
Do you know I can tell you exactly why one appears in the sky,
但我还没欣赏过它的美丽
but considering its beauty has always been out of the question.
在这里，你会改变的
Not here.
史波克
Spock.
是的，你想怎样？
Yes, what did you want?
史波克，是你吗？
Spock, is that you?
是的，舰长，你到底想干嘛？
Yes, captain. What did you want?
你在哪？
Where are you?
我不想说
I don't believe I want to tell you.
史波克，我不知道你怎么了
Spock, I don't know what you think you're doing,
但这是命令
but this is an order.
10分钟内回到定居点向我报到
Report back to me at the settlement in ten minutes.
我们要把所有的居民撤到第27号星际基地
We're evacuating all colonists to Starbase 27.
不，我拒绝
No, I don't think so.
你拒绝什么？
You don't think so, what?
我拒绝，长官
I don't think so, sir.
史波克
Spock.
赶紧向我报到
Report to me immediately.
史波克
Spock.
快回复
Acknowledge.
史波克
Spock.
通讯没有中断，但他不回复了
The frequency is open, but he doesn't answer.
那听起来一点也不像是史波克，吉姆
That didn't sound at all like Spock, Jim.
是的
No--
你不是说希望他能圆滑一点吗
I thought you said you might like him if he mellowed a little.
- 我可没那么说过 - 你说过的，我…
- I didn't say that. - You said that. I--
不是的
Not exactly.
他可能有麻烦了
He might be in trouble.
没错，你负责接管登陆部队
Yes, take over the landing party detail.
把居民送上星舰
Start getting those colonists aboard.
你怎么找史波克？
How will you find Spock?
他的通讯装置还开着，可以被定位
The frequency is open. It'll act as a homing device.
联系德赛尔，让他来这和你会合
Contact DeSalle. Have him meet you here.
把登陆部队分成二人小组
Make sure the landing party works in teams of two.
我不希望有任何人落单
I don't want anybody left alone down here.
史波克
Spock.
史波克先生？
Mr. Spock?
你在干什么，德赛尔？
What are you doing with those things, DeSalle?
希望你能看看这些东西，医生
Want you to take a good close look at these, doc.
你可能会感兴趣的
They're very interesting.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
你疯了吗？
Are you out of your mind?
你应该立即汇报
You were told to report to me at once.
我不想汇报，吉姆
I didn't want to, Jim.
是的，看得出来
Yes, I can see that.
卡罗米小姐，希望你能跟我们回定居点
Miss Kalomi, you'll have to come back with us to the settlement
准备前往星舰
and prepare to transport up to the ship.
不需要撤离了，吉姆
There'll be no evacuation, Jim.
也许我们该回去让你清醒清醒
But perhaps we should go back and get you straightened out.
苏鲁，抓住史波克
Mr. Sulu, Mr. Spock is under arrest,
看好他，直到我们回到进取号
and he's in your custody until we get back to the Enterprise.
好
Very well.
跟我来
Come with me.
苏鲁先生，现在明白了吗？
Mr. Sulu understands, don't you, Mr. Sulu?
是的，我明白了
Yes. I see now.
我们不应该对居民进行撤离
Of course we can't remove the colony. It'd be wrong.
我不知道这是什么植物，也不知道它做了什么
I don't know what these plants are or how they work on you,
但我命令你们跟我回村里去
but you're all going back to the settlement with me,
而且，撤离任务如期执行
and those colonists are going aboard the ship.
看来舰长要变得孤立无援了
I can see the captain is going to be difficult.
准备传送
Ready to beam up.
嘿，小吉姆
Hiya, Jimmy boy.
嘿，我已经处理好所有事了
Hey, I've taken care of everything.
你尽管放心
Now, all y'all gotta do is just relax.
这是医嘱
Doctor's orders.
你送上去多少人了？
How many of those did you beam up?
大概100人
Must be might nigh on to 1 00 by now.
医生，传送装置准备就绪了
Hey, doc, I'm ready to energize.
那些植物还好吗？
Everything okay with those plants?
我是舰长，把我传送上去
This is the captain. Beam me up.
好的
Well, sure. If you want.
开始吧
I most certainly do. Energize.
上尉
Lieutenant.
给我联系星际舰队的寇马克上将
Put me through to Admiral Komack at Starfleet.
抱歉，舰长
Oh, I'm sorry, captain.
我做不到
I can't do that.
你是什么意思？
What do you mean, you can't do that?
按标准程序通讯，这是命令
Follow standard procedure, that's an order.
我知道，舰长
I know it is, captain.
但所有通讯都中断了
But you see, all communications are out.
中断了？
Out?
我把它们都切断了
I short-circuited them.
除了和殖民地的通讯，我们还用得着
Except for ship-to-surface, we'll need that for a while.
这是为了大家好，舰长
It's really for the best, captain.
回到各自岗位
Go back to your stations.
Get back to your stations.
抱歉，长官，我们要加入那些殖民者
I'm sorry, sir. We're all transporting down to join the colony.
我命令你们回到各自岗位
I said, get back to your station.
不，长官
No, sir.
你们这是在造反
This is mutiny, mister.
没错，是的
Yes, sir, it is.
舰长日志，星历3417.5
Captain's log, stardate 3417.5.
那种植物孢子经过通风系统
The pod plants have spread spores throughout the ship,
播散到了整个星舰
carried by the ventilation system.
在它们的作用之下
Under their influence,
我的部下们热切地希望加入ο星殖民地
my crew is deserting to join the Omicron colony,
而我却无能为力
and I can't stop them.
不知为何我没受影响
I don't know why I have not been infected,
我也没办法让麦考伊
nor can I get Dr. McCoy
向我解释这些孢子对人的身心影响
to explain the physical-psychological aspects of the infection.
吉姆，我没兴趣
I'm not interested
解释这些东西
in any physical-psychological aspects, Jim boy.
我们在这里都很健康
We all perfectly healthy down here.
我已经听腻了
I've heard that word a lot lately.
“完美”这个词
"Perfect." Everything's perfect.
是的，但事实就是如此
Yeah, that's right. That's just what it is.
我想你连扁桃体都长出来了
I'll bet you've even grown your tonsils back.
没错
Sure enough.
嘿，小吉姆
Hey, Jim boy.
你尝过乔治亚式的冰镇薄荷酒吗？
Y'all ever have a real cold, Georgia-style mint julep, huh?
听着，老骨头，我需要你的帮助
Look, Bones, I need your help.
你能进行什么测试，来帮我们研究
Can you run tests, blood samples, anything at all to give us a lead
这些植物的性质，找到摆脱影响的方法吗？
on what these things are, how to counteract them?
我才不想离开天堂呢，小吉姆
Who wants to counteract paradise, Jim boy?
麦考伊呼叫完毕
McCoy out.
老骨头，老骨头
Bones. Bones.
现在几乎所有舰队成员都下来了
Almost the entire ship's complement has beamed down.
我非常高兴
I'm very pleased.
登陆计划现在进行得非常顺利
The entire landing operation is proceeding quite well.
麦考伊在哪？
Where's McCoy?
他去调制薄荷酒了
He went off to create something called a mint julep.
是一种饮料，吉姆
That's a drink, Jim.
舰长，为什么你不加入我们呢？
Captain, why don't you join us?
加入你们所谓的天堂？
In your own private paradise?
这都是那些孢子的功劳
The spores have made it that.
它们来自哪里？
Where did they originate?
这个很难说
It's impossible to say.
它们在太空中漂流，直至在这里生根发芽
They drifted through space until they finally landed here.
它们能在博托射线照射下茁壮成长
You see, they actually thrive on Berthold rays.
数以千计的微小孢子藏身于那种植物体内
The plants act as a repository for thousands of microscopic spores
直到它们找到人类宿主
until they find a human body to inhabit.
作为回报，它们给人带来健康和安宁
In return, they give you complete health and peace of mind.
让人仿佛置身于天堂
That's paradise.
我们无欲无求，舰长
We have no need or want, captain.
这里是真正的伊甸园，吉姆
It's a true Eden, Jim.
有爱和归属
There's belonging and love.
无欲无求？
No wants, no needs?
可我们并不应该这样
We weren't meant for that. None of us.
如果没有需求，没有欲望
Man stagnates if he has no ambition,
人类的发展就会停滞不前
no desire to be more than he is.
我们有我们需要的东西
We have what we need.
但你们的生活没有挑战
Except a challenge.
你不明白，吉姆
You don't understand, Jim.
但你迟早会回来的
But you'll come around, sooner or later.
加入我们吧
Join us.
好吗
Please.
我要回星舰了
I'm going back to the ship.
轮机室，斯科特？
Engineering. Scotty?
生化实验室
Biochemistry lab.
安保
Security.
还有人在舰上吗，我是舰长
Is there anyone onboard? This is the captain.
舰长日志，星历3417.7
Captain's log, stardate 3417.7.
除了我以外
Except for myself,
全体船员都登陆到了星球上
all crew personnel have transported to the surface of the planet.
一场哗变
Mutinied.
乌苏拉上尉完全破坏了
Lieutenant Uhura has effectively sabotaged
通讯装置
the communications station.
我只能与星球取得联系
I can only contact the surface of the planet.
星舰可以在轨道上运行数月
The ship can be maintained in orbit for several months.
但即使有自动操控系统，我也无法独自驾驶
But even with automatic controls, I cannot pilot her alone.
我已经被困在了这里
In effect, I am marooned here.
我开始意识到…
I'm beginning to realise...
…这艘星舰是如此宏伟，如此的安静
...just how big this ship really is, how quiet.
我不知道怎样才能让我的船员回来
I don't know how to get my crew back,
怎样才能对抗那些孢子的作用
how to counteract the effect of the spores.
我不知道如何对抗…
I don't know what I can offer against...
…天堂
...paradise.
进取号呼叫史波克
Enterprise to Mr. Spock.
吉姆，怎么了？
Yes, Jim, what is it now?
我加入你们了
I've joined you.
我明白了
I understand now.
太好了，吉姆
Wonderful, Jim.
你什么时候下来？
When will you beam down?
我还有一些东西要收拾
There are some things in my quarters I want to pack.
好
Good.
我和利拉会在传送点等你
Leila and I will meet you at the beam-down point.
寇克呼叫完毕
Kirk out.
不
No.
我…
I...
…不能…
...can't...
…走！
...leave!
情绪
Emotions.
强烈的情绪，欲望
Violent emotions. Needs.
愤怒
Anger.
舰长日志，补充记录
Captain's log, supplemental.
我似乎找到了答案
I think I've discovered the answer.
但要实现我的计划，需要冒一点风险
But to carry out my plan entails considerable risk.
史波克比一般的人更强大
Mr. Spock is much stronger than the ordinary human being.
要是激怒了他，他可以轻而易举地掐死我
Aroused, his great physical strength could kill.
但我必须冒这个险
But it's a risk I'll have to take.
进取号呼叫史波克
Enterprise to Mr. Spock.
我是史波克
Spock here.
我是吉姆
It's Jim.
怎么还没下来，吉姆？我们在等你呢
What's keeping you, Jim? We've been waiting.
我在收拾东西的时候发现了一些装备
I've been packing some things, and I realised there's some equipment here
也许能在下面派上用场
that we should have down at the settlement.
如果现在不拿下去，就没机会再回来拿了
You know, we can't come back onboard once the last of us has left.
我要派一支小队帮你吗？
Do you want me to beam up a party?
不，我想你我两人就够了
No, I think you and I can handle it.
你现在能上来吗？
Why don't you beam up now?
等等
Just a moment.
- 我很快就回来，好吗？ - 我等你
- It won't take long. Do you mind? - I'll wait.
我准备好了，吉姆
Ready to beam up, Jim.
启动
Energizing.
你这个叛徒，不忠的、程序化的杂种
All right, you mutinous, disloyal, computerised half-breed.
居然让我的舰队变成了这样
We'll see about you deserting my ship.
你说我是“杂种”，我可以理解
The term "half-breed" is somewhat applicable.
但“程序化”说得并不准确
But "computerised" is inaccurate.
机器可以是程序化的，但人不可以
A machine can be computerised, not a man.
你以为你是人？你只是一只体型过大的长耳野兔
What makes you think you're a man? You're an overgrown jackrabbit.
甲状腺亢奋的怪物
An elf with a hyperactive thyroid.
- 吉姆，我不明白 - 你当然不明白
- Jim, I don't understand. - Of course you don't understand.
你根本没有脑子
You don't have the brains to understand.
你的脑袋里装的只是一些电路
All you have is printed circuits.
- 舰长，我想我要失陪了 - 你觉得一个由机器和百科全书所生的
- Captain, if you'll excuse me-- - What can you expect
只会傻笑，耳朵长得像怪物的杂种
from a simpering, devil-eared freak whose father was a computer
脑子里能有些什么东西？
and his mother an encyclopaedia?
我的母亲是一名教师
My mother was a teacher.
而我的父亲，是一名大使
My father, an ambassador.
你的父亲是一台机器，就和你一样
Your father was a computer, like his son.
一个来自充满叛徒的星球的大使
An ambassador from a planet of traitors.
瓦肯人完全没有诚信可言
A Vulcan never lived who had an ounce of integrity.
舰长，请不要再…
Captain, please don't--
你和你的族人一样，都是叛徒
You're a traitor from a race of traitors.
对上级不忠，你和你的低等种族都会下地狱的
Disloyal to the core. Rotten like the rest of your subhuman race.
你还有胆子去和那个女的鬼混
And you've got the gall to make love to that girl.
够了
That's enough.
她知道你是什么东西吗，史波克？
Does she know what she's getting, Spock?
一个会说话的，等着发霉的
A carcass full of memory banks
行尸走肉
who should be squatting on a mushroom
而不是一个活人
instead of passing himself off as a man?
你应该去马戏团跟小丑待在一起
You belong in a circus, Spock, not a starship.
而不是来这里
Right next to the dog-faced boy.
怎么样了？
Had enough?
我没想到你生气了会是这样
I didn't realise what it took to get under that thick hide of yours.
不过无论如何
Anyhow, I don't know what you're so mad about.
不是每个大副都有机会这样狠揍舰长
It isn't every first officer who gets to belt his captain.
好几次
Several times.
你是故意侮辱我的
You did that to me deliberately.
相信我，史波克
Believe me, Mr. Spock,
受伤的不只是你
it was painful in more ways than one.
那些孢子
The spores.
作用消失了
They're gone.
我清醒过来了
I don't belong anymore.
你说它们给你带来了安宁
You said they were benevolent and peaceful.
激烈的情绪能对抗并且消灭它们
Violent emotions overwhelm them, destroy them.
我必须激怒你以摆脱它们的影响
I had to make you angry enough to shake off their influence.
那就是答案，史波克
That's the answer, Mr. Spock.
你也许是对的，舰长
That may be correct, captain.
但要通过这种方式
But trying to initiate a brawl
让超过500名船员恢复理智是不切实际的
with over 500 crew men and colonists is hardly logical.
我有一个办法
I had something else in mind.
你能制造一个次声发射机吗？
Can you put together a subsonic transmitter?
我们可以用它来入侵通讯站
Something we could hook into the communications station
把信息广播出去
and broadcast over the communicator?
- 可以 - 好的，我们开始吧
- It can be done. - Good. Let's get to work.
舰长
Captain.
攻击舰队官员是一项重罪
Striking a fellow officer is a court-martial offence.
但如果我们都进了禁闭室
Well, if we're both in the brig,
谁来制造发射机？
who's gonna build the subsonic transmitter?
你说的的确符合逻辑，舰长
That is quite logical, captain.
利拉小姐，现在就开始数星星好像有点早了
Well, now, it's a little early to be counting stars, Miss Leila.
我在等史波克和舰长下来
I'm waiting for Mr. Spock and the captain to transport down.
他们还要拿一些装备
They have some equipment to be moved.
但他们已经在上面待了很久了
But it's been so long.
我希望他们能早点下来
I wish he'd come back.
让我来帮帮你吧
Well, now, I think I can fix that for you.
呼叫进取号
Enterprise.
这里是进取号，我是史波克
Enterprise. Spock here.
我是利拉
This is Leila.
我借了医生的通讯器
I borrowed the doctor's communicator.
我还在担心你
I was worried something might have happened to you.
你还好吧？
You are all right, aren't you?
是的
Yes.
是的，我…我很好
Yes, I'm-- I'm quite well.
我能上去吗？
Can I come aboard?
我还没参观过星舰
I've never seen a starship before.
我想见你
And I want to talk to you.
你还在传送点吗？
Are you still at the beam-down point?
医疗官在那吗？
And is the doctor there?
是的，我们都在
Yes, to both questions.
把你的通讯器给麦考伊医生吧
Give your communicator back to Dr. McCoy.
你不用带着那个上来
You won't need it to beam up.
可能要花一点时间，你等等
It'll take a few moments. Just wait there.
呼叫完毕
Out.
史波克
Mr. Spock.
我不该干涉你和卡罗米小姐
Miss Kalomi is strictly your concern, but should you talk to her
但她现在还带着孢子，你不该和她讲话吧？
while she's still under the influence of the spores?
我很快就回来
I'll be back shortly, captain.
你已经不属于我们了，是吗？
You're no longer with us, are you?
我感到了异常
I felt something was wrong.
我必须这么做
It was necessary.
跟我回去吧
Come back to the planet with me.
你可以重新成为我们的一员
You can belong again.
跟我回去吧，求你了
Come back with me, please.
不行
I can't.
我爱你
I love you.
我六年前就说过了
I said that six years ago,
我的心从来就没变过
and I can't seem to stop repeating myself.
在地球上的时候，你没做任何表示
On Earth, you couldn't give anything of yourself.
连拥抱都没有过
You couldn't even put your arms around me.
我们的爱情没法在那里开花结果
We couldn't have anything together there.
在别的地方也是如此
We couldn't have anything together anyplace else.
但在这里，我们都会快乐
But we're happy here.
我不能失去你，史波克，我不能
I can't lose you now, Mr. Spock. I can't.
我必须对这艘星舰负责
I have a responsibility to this ship.
对舰桥上的那个男人负责
To that man on the bridge.
我就是我，利拉
I am what I am, Leila,
如果每个人都不得不
and if there are self-made purgatories,
生活在自己造就的炼狱中
and we all have to live in them,
我的人生并不是最糟糕的
mine can be no worse than someone else's.
我已经失去你了，是吗？
I have lost you, haven't I?
不止是你
Not only you.
还有它们
I've lost all of it.
那些孢子
The spores.
它们的作用消失了
I've lost them too.
舰长发现，强烈的情绪
The captain discovered that strong emotions
还有欲望可以抵抗那些孢子的影响
and needs destroy the spore influence.
这是为了我好吗？
And this is for my good?
我能继续爱你吗？
Do you mind if I say I still love you?
你还没告诉过我你的另一个名字，史波克
You never told me if you had another name, Mr. Spock.
你念不出来
You couldn't pronounce it.
他们不会直接听到这些信息
They'll not hear this, of course.
但他们会感受得到
It'll be more of a sensation of feeling it.
就像有人把痒粉洒在他们身上
As though somebody had put itching powder on their skin.
没错
Precisely.
几分钟之后就会起效了
Now, it should begin to work on their nerves in a few minutes.
- 抱歉，德赛尔 - 你这是在干什么？
- Sorry, DeSalle. - What do you think you're doing?
- 我说了，对不起 - 真是笨手笨脚的
- I said I was sorry. - More like you're clumsy.
如果你没挡着我的道…
If you hadn't gotten in my way...
别打了，别打了
Come on, break it up. Break it up.
嘿，医生
Well, doctor,
我一直在想应该给你安排什么工作
I've been thinking about what sort of work I can assign you to.
你这是什么意思？
What do you mean?
什么工作？我是医生
What sort of work? I'm a doctor.
不，不再是了
Not anymore, of course.
我们不需要医生
We don't need you. Not as a doctor.
不需要？
Oh, no?
你信不信我现在就把你打到进医院？
Would you like to see just how fast I can put you in a hospital?
我是这个殖民地的首领
I am the leader of this colony.
我会给你安排任何我觉得合适的工作
I'll assign you to whatever work I think is suitable.
等等
Just a minute.
最好让我当个技工
Better make me a mechanic.
这样我就可以修理你了
Then I can treat little tin gods like you.
对不起，桑多瓦尔
Sorry, Sandoval.
我不知道我是怎么了
I don't know what made me do that.
我们在这里什么都没干
We've done nothing here.
没有成就，没有进展
No accomplishments. No progress.
浪费了三年时间
Three years wasted.
我们希望把这个星球改造成花园
We wanted to make this planet a garden.
你不能留在这里了
You can't stay here.
没有了那些孢子，你活不下去的
You can't survive without the spores.
到达星际基地之后，你可以重新开始
After you've cleared at the starbase, you could be relocated.
去你想去的地方
It depends upon what you want.
我想我…
I think I'd...
我想我会继续工作
I think we'd like to get some work done.
完成以前的理想
The work we started out to do.
呼叫进取号
Enterprise.
这里是进取号，我是史波克
Enterprise. Spock here.
我是麦考伊
This is McCoy.
桑多瓦尔想和舰长谈谈
Sandoval would like to talk to the captain.
等等
Just a moment.
他们开始跟我们联系了
They're all beginning to call in, captain.
好像有点懊恼
Rather contritely, I should say.
桑多瓦尔希望和你谈谈
Sandoval wishes to speak to you.
打开扬声器，我是寇克
Put him on the speaker. Kirk here.
舰长，我之前听说你要把我们送到27号星际基地
Captain, as I understood it, you were to transport us to Starbase 27.
我们会配合你们
We'll give you every cooperation.
开始准备吧，桑多瓦尔先生
Start making preparations, Mr. Sandoval.
等我们的船员都上来后
We'll begin transporting your people aboard
就开始传送你们的人
as soon as more of our crew checks in.
吉姆，我刚检查完最后一个居民
Well, Jim, I've just examined the last of the colonists.
他们都很健康
They're all in absolutely perfect, perfect health.
这是那些孢子带来的小福利
A fringe benefit left over by the spores.
很好
Good.
这是人们第二次被赶出天堂了
Well, that's the second time man's been thrown out of paradise.
不，老骨头，这次是我们自己走出来的
No, no, Bones. This time we walked out on our own.
也许天堂并不适合我们
Maybe we weren't meant for paradise.
也许我们就应该不断奋斗
Maybe we were meant to fight our way through.
挣扎，努力，一步一步地走
Struggle, claw our way up, scratch for every inch of the way.
我们也许无法控制生活的节奏
Maybe we can't stroll to the music of the lute.
但我们必须紧跟这种节奏
We must march to the sound of drums.
这是在吟诗吗，舰长？
Poetry, captain?
不像是你啊
Non-regulation.
你对这次行动有什么感想呢，史波克
We haven't heard much from you about Omicron Ceti III, Mr. Spock.
我没有什么想说的，舰长
I have little to say about it, captain.
不过…
Except that...
…一生之中我第一次
...for the first time in my life,
觉得快乐
I was happy.
TLF字幕组欢迎你，欢迎有志之士加入
TLF中文字幕站http://tlfsubs.eastgame.org/